

CURRICULUM VITAE

Name: Zaman Gahramanov

Date of birth: 16/12/1984

Nationality: Azerbaijani

Marital status: single

Sex: Male

Address: Bag Park 1, Binagadi district AZ1114, Baku Azerbaijan

Telephone: (+994) 50 221-41-71

Email: zaman.gahramanov@gmail.com

PERSONAL SUMMARY

A highly efficient and competent Legal Individual with an ability to ensure that a company complies and operates in accordance with statutory and legal provisions. Experience of attending meetings with company shareholders and the board of directors and acting as a point of communication between them. Well-presented and highly personable, with a deep knowledge of Contract Law, Common and Civil Law, corporate regulatory and company rules. Excellent organizational skills, highly efficient and methodical with a good eye for detail.

Work experience:

16/12/2015 – Present, **State Oil Company of the Republic of Azerbaijan (SOCAR) / Investments Department.**

Job title: Senior Legal Counsel

Job Description / Duties:

- 1. Provide legal support in the drafting and negotiation of any amendments to the JV agreements and related documentation.
- 2. Provide legal support in negotiations with JV partners.
- 3. Provide legal support in Project and Corporate Financing and related negotiations, both internally and externally.
- 4. Provide legal support in the drafting and negotiation of new JV agreements and pertinent documentation, as well as the development of standard documents and templates.
- 5. Draft and negotiate all forms of agreements, memorandum of agreements, purchase agreements, memorandum of understanding, deeds, undertakings, merger & acquisition agreements.
- 6. Apply effective risk management techniques and offer proactive advise on possible legal issues

01/04/2016 - 04/07/2017, **ZafaMart.Az**

Job title: Management Consultant / Co-owner

Website: http://www.zafamart.az

Job Description / Duties:

- 1. Provide strategic, unbiased and objective advisory services which assist organization in improving productivity and overall performance;
- 2. Providing with the advisory activity on areas such as change management, financial performance, marketing, business restructuring, and human resources, with an emphasis on managing risks and costs.

22/10/2012 – 15/12/2015, Azerbaijan (ACG) Limited (SOCAR).

Job title: *Legal Manager* (chief of division)

Job Description / Duties:

- 1. Providing legal protection and risk management advice to management on contract management.
- 2. Review and draft contracts, agreements and internal policies and ensure that they are in compliance with all statutory or legal requirements.
- 3. Review and provide legal advice on tender documents.
- 4. Securing company and its all possessions from any illegal problems.
- 5. Performing various tasks related to legal matters in a company.
- 6. Studying contracts and legal documents to make sure that it is in the organization's interests.
- 7. Report preparation for assessment and presentation before the senior officials.
- 8. Preparation legal documents, Loan Agreements, Software Licensing Agreements, Construction Agreements, Service Frame Agreements, Labor

Agreements, NDA Agreements, Framework Technical Co-operation Agreements, Sale-Purchase Agreements, Research Agreements, Lease Agreements and any

legal documentation necessary for the business requirements.

9. Assumption of crucial actions regarding legal matters and controversial issues.

15/03/2011 - 27/09/2011 Azersu Joint Stock Company of Azerbaijan Republic.

Job title: Senior Legal Adviser

Job Description / Duties:

- 1. Providing accurate, timely and effective legal advice to the head of legal department of the company.
- 2. Work on negotiating and drafting contracts.
- 3. Providing a legal advice on the potential liability, in order to take essential steps to control the company exposure.
- 4. Assess actual, potential or perceived risks in contracts and legal documents and accordingly providing professional legal expertise.

28/09/2010 – 15/03/2011 **Practical solutions Group in Azerbaijan Republic.**

Job title: Legal Adviser

Job Description / Duties:

- 1. Attending hearings in a court.
- 2. Preparing arguments to be heard in a trial.
- 3. Draft contracts that minimize risks and maximize legal rights.

01/09/2008 - 02/03/2009 The Republic of Azerbaijan Ministry of Economy.

Job title: Senior Adviser

Job Description / Duties:

- 1. Control of consumer goods in market.
- 2. Prevention restriction of competition in a market
- 3. Protection rights of the consumers.
- 4. Control of supplying the goods and services in a manner allowed by the policy of the government.

Professional Experience

Legal competencies

- Possessing the ability to convincingly present a case in court.
- Good knowledge of civil law, international commercial arbitration law, international private law, company law, international commercial and contract law.
- Understanding of contracts, government regulations, intellectual property rights, patents etc.
- Knowledge of tax and corporate law.
- Knowledge of Employment law.
- Legal advice.
- Contract Negotiation

Personal

- Ability to balance priorities and co-ordinate work effectively.
- Leadership skills.
- Excellent analytical skills.
- Ability to stay calm under pressure.
- Can analyze large amounts of information.
- Good written and spoken communication skills.
- Organized and efficient.
- Good project management and team building skills.

Education

- 2011-2012 LLM Master Degree (International Business and Commercial Law) The University of Manchester.
- 2006 2008 Master in Laws (LLM) Baku State University
- 2001 2005 Faculty of Law- Baku State University, Bachelor Degree

Publications

- 1. The Role of Arbitrators in International Commercial Arbitration. Issues of Immunity, Independence and Impartiality.
- 2. The meaning of the terms "object" and "effect" in Article 101 of the TFEU.

Training Courses:

• International Joint Ventures and Strategic Alliances in the Oil and Gas

Industry.

- Basic knowledge to work in the foreign exchange market.
- Oil & Gas Workshop: Acquisitions and joint ventures in oil and gas sector
- Presentation Skills
- Time Management
- Damages, Default, Indemnities and Force Majeure in International Oil and Gas Contracts
- Introduction to ISO 9001: 2008

Military Service

01/07/2005 - 02/07/2006

Languages

Azerbaijani (native proficiency) Russian (full professional proficiency) English (full professional proficiency) Turkish (professional proficiency)

Computer Skills

Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Power Point, etc.).

Expected Monthly Wage

Negotiable